<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!DOCTYPE node PUBLIC "-//freedesktop//DTD D-BUS Object Introspection 1.0//EN" "http://www.freedesktop.org/standards/dbus/1.0/introspect.dtd">
<node xmlns:doc="http://www.freedesktop.org/dbus/1.0/doc.dtd">
    <interface name="org.gnome.SessionManager.ClientPrivate">
        <method name="EndSessionResponse">
            <arg name="is_ok" type="b" direction="in">
                <summary>Whether or not it is OK to proceed</summary>
            </arg>
            <arg name="reason" type="s" direction="in">
                <summary>The reason string</summary>
            </arg>
            <description>This method should be used by the client in response to the QueryEndSession and EndSession signals.</description>
        </method>

        <signal name="Stop">
            <arg name="placeholder" type="b" />
            <description>The client should stop and remove itself from the session in response to this signal.</description>
        </signal>

        <signal name="QueryEndSession">
            <arg name="flags" type="u">
                <summary>Flags</summary>
            </arg>
            <description>This signal is used to inform the client that the session is about to end.  The client must respond 
            by calling EndSessionResponse within one second of the signal emission. If the client responds with an EndSessionResponse
            is-ok argument equal to FALSE and a reason then this reason may be displayed to the user. The client must not attempt to
            perform any actions or interact with the user in response to this signal.  Any actions required for a clean shutdown should
            take place in response to the EndSession signal. The client should limit operations until either a EndSession or CancelEndSession
            signal is received.</description>
        </signal>

        <signal name="EndSession">
            <arg name="flags" type="u">
                <summary>Flags</summary>
            </arg>
            <description>This signal is used to inform the client that the session is about to end.  The client must respond by
            calling EndSessionResponse within ten seconds of the signal emission. The client must not attempt to interact with
            the user in response to this signal. The application will be given a maximum of ten seconds to perform any actions required
            for a clean shutdown.</description>
        </signal>

        <signal name="CancelEndSession">
            <arg name="placeholder" type="b" />
            <description>This signal indicates to the client that a previous emission ofQueryEndSession has been cancelled.
            The client should resume normal operations.</description>
        </signal>

    </interface>
</node>
